字幕转制｜天外生物
感谢原字幕制作者
- 嗯！ - 嘿
- Mmm!  - Hey.
嘿，为什么我们以前从没在一起？
Hey, how come we never got together before?
因为我一直有男朋友
Well, because I always had a boyfriend.
现在还有吗？
You still got one?
如果我在舞会上甩了你，你还会是我男朋友吗？
Would you still be my boyfriend if I ditched you at the prom?
不可能的事
Never happen.
- 当心点，公主殿下  - 让我来开
- Watch it, your highness.  - Let me drive.
- 我来开  - 不，这可不…
- I wanna drive.  - No, I don't think...
让我开，我给你的手找了个更好的地方
Let me drive. I got a better place for your hand.
噢！耶！
Oh, yeah.
♪ You might think I'm crazy ♪
用鼻子吸气
Inhale through your nose.
用嘴呼气
Exhale through your mouth.
向右转动方向盘
Turn the wheel to the right.
用鼻子吸气
Inhale through your nose.
呼气，向左转动方向盘
Exhale, turn the wheel to the left.
用鼻子吸气
Inhale through your nose.
向右转动方向盘
Turn the wheel to the right.
非常好，好的，准备好了吗？
Oh, very good. Okay, ready?
哦，艾玛的头球
Oh, Irma hit it with her head!
来击下掌，干得漂亮
Gimme five on that. Right here. Good job.
今天想系什么颜色的缎带？蓝色还是桃色？
what color ribbon would you like today: Blue or peach?
- 你明白了？ - 好的
- You got it?  - All right.
这很容易
Easy does it.
我想洗澡
I wanna have my bath now.
你已经洗过了，狄娅娜
You already had your bath, Diane.
- 中风吗？ - 他们是这么说的
- Stroke, huh?  - That's what they told me.
- 谢谢  - 不客气
- Thanks.  - You're welcome.
我想现在可以松开他了
I think we can remove his restraints now.
他是该象其他犯人一样对待
I know he deserves the same care as anyone else,
但我们确实无法适应政府的做法
but we're really not set up to accommodate the state's overflow.
嘿，我已经松开了
Hey, I just move 'em.
卡萝
Carol!
签个字吧
Just, uh, sign here.
你能送曼宁先生去一一四号房吗？
Would you please take Mr. Manning to 114?
能跟上手势吗？
Can you follow this?
能捏紧吗？
How about a little squeeze?
他们干嘛那样铐着你？
Man, why'd they have you chained up like that?
- 他是个重罪犯  - 嘘！
- He's a felon.  - Shh!
女士们，你们该了解些更好的事，去吧
Ladies, you should know better than that. Go on.
以后有的是时间来拜访
There's plenty of time to visit later.
去吧
Go.
在这没有太多私人空间
Not a lot of privacy around here,
但考虑到你的来路
but considering where you've been,
多一点女性关注也许是好事
a little female attention might be nice.
好吧，来点音乐怎么样？
Right. How 'bout a little music?
有摇滚，也有爵士
We got rock 'n' roll. We got jazz.
还有乡村音乐，我们有很多乡村音乐
We got country. We got lots of country here.
工作怎么样？
How was work?
还行
Okay.
来了个新病人
Got a new guy in.
- 猜猜是什么人？ - 什么人？
- Guess what he was?  - What?
银行大盗
A bank robber.
而且是高手，他们花了三十年才抓到他
Pretty good one too. Took them 30 years to catch him.
- 要归功于一次停电  - 他为什么失去知觉？
- The only reason they did was a blackout.  - Why'd he black out?
不是他失去知觉
He didn't black out.
[停电和失去知觉为同一词]
是丹佛全城停电
Denver did. The whole city.
应急发电机坏了
The emergency generator kicked in.
金库关闭，第二天他们打开金库时…
The vault shuts, and the next day when they open the vault...
钥匙在车上吗？
Are the keys in the car?
- 是的  - 好的，明天见
- Yeah.  - Okay. See you in the morning.
他们在金库里发现了他
They found him in the vault.
天亮了
Rise and shine.
太平洋西北地区的又一个好日子
It's another beautiful day in the Pacific Northwest,
我们俄州地区预计该是晴天
and our Oregon forecast promises sunshine.
亲爱的？
Honey?
谢谢
Thank you.
卡萝
Carol.
怎么样？你和我？
How 'bout it? You and me?
要是我丈夫还活着的话，哈
If my husband were alive, hah!
看起来很不错
This looks pretty good.
你是在回忆往事
Are you in there remembering it all,
还是一切都无从记起了？
or did everything just get erased?
他有什么问题？
What's his problem?
中风，你的理由呢？
He had a stroke. What's your excuse?
噢！
Uh-oh.
你在生我气？
Are you mad at me?
你真的对我生气了？
You're really gonna be mad at me?
你说好要开车送我的
You said you were gonna drive me to work.
见鬼，看看你
Damn. Look at you.
你那么美，知道你有多美吗？
You are so beautiful. You know how beautiful you are?
我生气时你总这么说
You always say that to me when I'm mad at you.
一针见血
Beats fightin'.
那么，你去哪了？
So? Where were you?
是工作上的事
Um... It was a work thing.
- 是吗？ - 是的
- Really?  - Yeah.
同老板喝酒，这差使不容易
Drinking with the boss, that's hard work.
不过…
But...
你面前是个主管了
You're lookin' at a supervisor.
- 真的？ - 嗯
- Really?  - Mm-hmm.
- 日班？ - 我哪知道你会有这要求？
- Day shift?  - How did I know you were gonna ask that?
但加了八十块，全额退休金…
But it is 80 bucks raise...
福利，合计有九百
and a full pension, benefits, the whole nine yards.
- 退休金  - 这样等你老了就不用吃猫粮
- Pension.  - So you don't have to eat cat food when you get old.
或者象这家伙一样可怜
Or wind up like this poor slob.
可悲的是，他也许有地方可以拿钱
The sad thing is, he probably has loads of money somewhere.
他就是我说的那个银行大盗
He's the guy I told you about, the bank robber.
我会尽快争取上日班，好吗？
Hey, I'll get on the day shift soon, okay?
能让我见到你当然好了
That would be nice. I could see you once in a while.
恭喜你，很高兴你能升职
Congratulations. I'm happy about the promotion.
♪ You might think it's hysterical ♪
♪ I know when you're weak ♪
♪ You think you're in the movies ♪
- 那么？ - 在这不行
- Now?  - You can't do this here!
♪ But I think that you're wild ♪
♪ When you flash that fragile smile ♪
♪ You might think it's foolish ♪
♪ What you put me through ♪
- ♪ You might think ♪  - ♪ You might think I'm crazy ♪
- ♪ All I want ♪  - ♪ All I want is you ♪
♪ And it was hard ♪
♪ So hard to take ♪
♪ There's no escape ♪
♪ Without a scrape ♪
♪ But you kept it goin' till the sun fell down ♪
♪ You kept it goin'♪
♪ The seasons will fade but one thing rem... ♪
她不能对我们这么乱来
She can't just go changing the rules on us like that.
惹急了我会去协会告她
And I'll go to the union if I have to. She knows I will.
帮我扶她起来
Help me lift her up.
好了，站起来
Okay, up you go.
哦！
Ohh!
- 没人能假装中风  - 他能
- No way can you fake a stroke.  - He could.
知道他干过什么吗？
Do you know what he did?
他出售安全系统给银行
He started a company that sold security systems to banks.
- 然后呢？ - 然后盗窃银行
- Yeah, so?  - And then he robbed the banks.
我见过他，但这些油菜卷心菜比他做过什么更要紧
I saw him. You know, this cole slaw's got more going on than he does.
也许你该培养点业余爱好
Maybe you need a hobby or something.
草莓，香蕉和苹果会浮上来
Well, your strawberries, bananas and apples float,
李子和桃子会沉下去
and your prunes and peaches sink.
你只要区分是浮是沉
You just have to tell the floaters from the sinkers.
有点象男人
Kinda like men.
我懂了，懂了
I got it, I got it. Okay.
我相信狱医对你做过彻底检查
I'll bet those prison doctors gave you a real going-over.
用针扎你
Sticking you with pins.
用锤子敲你
Whacking you with hammers.
有没有弄疼你？
Did they hurt you?
显然他们采用了错误的方案
Obviously, they took the wrong approach.
这就是医生和护士之间的差别
That's the difference between doctors and nurses.
医生在检查程序上可能有很多约束
Doctors can be so tied to medical procedures.
但有时候…
But sometimes...
一点点朴实的疗法会有效得多
a little down-home therapy is so much more effective.
♪ When she's dancing 'neath the starry sky ♪
♪ Ooh, she'll make you flip ♪
♪ Here she comes again ♪
♪ When she's dancing 'neath the starry sky ♪
♪ I kinda like the way she dips ♪
你嘴唇很干吗？
Are your lips dry?
♪ She's my best friend's girl ♪
所以才不能和我说话？
Is that why you can't speak to me?
♪ She's my best friend's girl ♪
♪ But she used to be mine ♪
放松的感觉是不是很好？
Wouldn't it feel good to just let go, hmm?
嗯？
Hmm?
我知道你在那
I know you're in there.
出来，出来，不管你在哪
Come out, come out, wherever you are.
♪ But when you bite your lip ♪
♪ It's a reaction to love ♪
- ♪ Here she comes again ♪  - ♪ When she's dancing 'neath the starry sky ♪
你抗拒的话治疗可能会大不一样
Therapy can be very difficult if you resist.
也许你需要到外边散散心
Maybe you need a less-structured environment.
♪ When she's dancing 'neath the starry sky ♪
你太好了，卡萝，尤其你是在休假
This is very thoughtful of you, Carol, especially on your day off,
但曼宁先生恐怕没能力对野餐表示感激
but I really don't think Mr. Manning will be able to appreciate a picnic.
我觉得他在内心深处会感激的
You know, Mrs. Foster, deep down inside, I think he will.
别担心，宝贝，我们会很开心的
Don't worry, baby. We're gonna have a great time.
当然，我们有啤酒，还有…
Well, sure. We got beer. We got, uh...
成人尿布
We got diapers.
要啤酒吗，亨利？
Want a beer, Henry?
我还以为他是指派的司机
I thought he was the designated driver.
- 鸡肉呢？ - 别戏弄这可怜的混蛋了
- How about a little chicken?  - Don't torture the poor bastard.
我没戏弄他，只是他太难对付了
I'm not torturing him. He's just being stubborn.
要是没女人献殷勤男人就不可能中风
Guy can't even have a stroke without some chick taking it personally, huh?
韦恩，你不是要去钓鱼吗？
Wayne, don't you have some fishing to do?
好了，亨利，这儿只有你和我了
Okay, Henry. It's just you and me.
我知道你能听见
I know you hear me.
这是你最后的机会
This is your last chance.
记住，这是你的选择
Just remember, this was your choice.
你就继续装好了
Didn't have to come to this.
我的天
Oh, my God.
啊！
Ah!
卡萝
Carol!
好吧，你很聪明
Okay, so you're smart.
非常聪明，你想怎样？
Really smart. What do you want?
一分钟前你还喋喋不休
A minute ago, you couldn't shut up.
现在却哑巴了？你想怎么样？
Now you can't talk, huh? What is it?
勒索我？你想分一杯羮是不是？
You lookin' to blackmail me? You're gonna put the bite on me, is that it?
- 卡萝，你敢碰她一个指头…  - 怎么，用水泼我吗？
- Carol! You lay a finger on her, and I'll...  - What, splash me?
说，你想怎么样？
Come on! Now, what do you want?
说啊
Come on!
- 我不知道  - 你不知道
- I don't know.  - You don't know.
我只是…不喜欢被愚弄
I just... I don't like being made a fool of.
我两年半前就开始这个花招了是吧？
Two and a half years I've been working on this hype, and that's it?
- 是的  - 真不敢相信
- That's it.  - I don't believe this.
你想怎样？
So, what are you gonna do?
我想怎样？你到底想怎样？还有他？
What am I gonna do? What the hell are you gonna do? And what about him, huh?
- 嘿！ - 你想怎样？
- Hey!  - And what about you?
什么我想怎样？
What about me what?
你想做英雄？把我送回监狱关几年？
You wanna be a hero, huh? You wanna stick me back in the slammer for a couple years?
你…你是说我会告密？
Are you... Is he... Are you calling me a rat?
哦，伙计
Oh, boy.
我要喝一杯
I need a drink.
说来有点可笑…
You know, it's funny the kind of stuff...
在监狱图书馆你能大有收获
that you can get shipped into a prison library.
佛教密宗，意念控制，自我催眠
Tantric Buddhism, mind control, autohypnosis.
必须…把所有这些融会贯通
Gotta... gather up all that stuff.
找出你需要的并为你所用，我那样做了
Find out what you need and make it work for you. I did that.
整日，整夜，每日，每夜
All day, all night. Every day, every night.
如同投入训练
Like I was in training.
对，我参加过体育训练
Yeah. I played sports.
假装中风并不完全象是…唔
Yeah, well, faking a stroke is not exactly like, uh,
一场竞技，但我得说…
an Olympic event, but I gotta tell ya,
如果你知道他们会替你输液
if you know they're gonna be stickin' pins in ya,
也知道有人一天二十四小时看守…
and you know that there are gonna be guards 24 hours a day...
等着你露出马脚
just waitin' for you to screw up on the hustle,
你就知道装死还装得不够好
then you know it ain't good enough to be just... playin' possum.
你必须来一次假死，绝对的假死
You gotta be a possum. Dead possum.
才能有用
So you work,
你要学着集中精神，抛开杂念
and you learn just to funnel... everything down,
最终你所知道的…
so finally all you know,
就是你只有心跳
all you are is a heartbeat.
我得告诉你，你可以到这样的状态
I gotta tell you, you get to a place like that,
到达一种类似死去的境界
it is some kick in the ass.
在体会一段时间后
Then you take that, and after a while,
你就能伪装并维持这状态直到…
you can shape it and mold it and squeeze it till...
我能让每次心跳听起来如同天籁之音
Hey, I can make every heartbeat sound like Frank Sinatra.
老天
Man.Yeah, man.
告诉你们…
I'll tell ya...
有一天，蟑螂…
One day, this cockroach...
爬上了我的领口
just climbed off my collar,
决定在我脸上漫游
decided to take a hike around my face,
之后停在了…
and he parked...
我的上嘴唇和鼻子之间
half on my upper lip and half inside my nose.
它在那儿挨挨擦擦
He just scratched around in there,
想找点刺激
lookin' for a little action.
那时你会祈盼有警卫巡视…
That's when you hope and pray there's a guard watching...
所以那一刻不会成为湮灭的往事
so that the moment won't be entirely lost to history.
不过，一段时间之后…
But, hey, after a while,
有几小时，那并不重要
a couple hours, doesn't matter.
只是一场竞赛而已…
Just a contest...
在天籁之音，你自己以及蟑螂之间
between Frank Sinatra, you and the cockroach.
那么谁赢了？
So who won?
而你还以为能凭一小段膝上舞唤醒我
And you thought that you could get a rise out of me with a little lap dance.
膝…膝上舞？
Lap... Lap dance?
那是…
It's, um...
治疗，类似于…臀部的东西
Therapy. Kind of... hippy stuff.
想跳舞吗？
You wanna dance?
来吧，你不反对吧？
Come on. It's okay with you?
当然，这有什么
Yeah, sure. What the hell.
这有什么
What the hell.
♪ Lie to me ♪
♪ And tell me that you'll stay here tonight ♪
♪ Tell me that you'll never leave ♪
象这样子你不担心吗？
Aren't you worried being seen like this?
你才应该担心
You're the one that ought to be worried.
人人都好奇你干嘛…
Everybody wondering what the hell you're doing...
和你的曾曾曾祖父跳舞
dancing with your great-great-great-great grandfather.
我从没和他跳过舞
I never danced with him.
常来这种地方吗？
So, come here often?
小姐，过去五年我每天都会来这
Lady, I've been coming here every day for the last five years.
你呢？
You?
算是常客
Often enough.
为什么不去别处？
Why don't you go someplace else?
这是镇里唯一的别处
It's the only someplace else in town.
换个镇试试
Try a new town.
你们在一起多久了？
How long you guys been goin' together?
不知道，从高中起吧
I don't know. Since high school.
我们是舞会的国王王后
We were king and queen of the prom.
有几点意思，国王，王后
Kind of made sense, you know. King, queen.
几时变得没有意思的？
When did it stop making sense?
♪ Oh, anyone can see ♪
♪ That you love him more than me ♪
♪ But right now, baby let me pretend ♪
♪ That our love will never end ♪
♪ Lie to me ♪
- ♪ Yeah, come on, baby ♪  - ♪ Go ahead and lie to me ♪
不赖，看起来你在监狱里经常跳舞
Not bad. Looks like you did a lot of dancing in the joint.
那都是男人，不一样
Those were guys. This is different.
放松点
Ow. Take it easy.
你还好吧？
Are you gonna be all right?
- 嗯？ - 我很好
- Huh?  - I'm okay.
你们都聊些什么？
What were you talking about?
怎么了？你在嫉妒
What? You're jealous.
我干嘛要嫉妒？
Why would I be jealous?
- 你就是在嫉妒  - 不可能
- You are. You're jealous.  - No way.
我是说，看他那副摇摇欲坠的样子
I mean, look at the guy. He's about to keel over.
他去哪了？卡萝
Where'd he go? Carol.
去洗手间看看
Check the men's room.
见鬼
Oh, goddamn it!
他跑了
He's gone.
拿走了车
He took the car.
不，我去叫警察
Oh, no. No, that's it. I'm calling the cops.
- 告诉他们什么？ - 一切
- And tell them what?  - Anything.
一不留神他就坐着轮椅不见了
We turned our backs, he was in the wheelchair, he was gone. I don't know.
是在我和他跳舞之前还是之后呢？
Oh, was that before or after I was seen dancing with him?
你不能叫警察
You can't call the cops.
你怎么能这样？
How could you do this?
是你的主意却得由我来收场
You come up with these ideas and I end up having to go along.
每次有麻烦了收场的是谁？是我
And every time, the shit hits the fan, who's gotta clean it up? Me!
现在我们怎么办？怎么办？
What are we gonna do here? What do we do?
我们怎么办？
What do we do, huh?
不知道
I don't know.
我们干嘛不修好“野马”
Why don't we fix the Mustang...
- 然后离开这鬼地方？ - 是的
- and just get the hell out of here?  - Yeah.
- 然后呢？ - 嗯
- And then what?  - Well,
到哪算哪直到找到喜欢的地方
just keep going till we find someplace we like.
知道吗？我就喜欢这里
You know what? I like it here just fine.
我没法早些打来
I couldn't call earlier.
我回头再解释，只管带着钱来找我
I'll explain later. Hey, just come and get me and bring the money.
有个火车站，离六号公路的疗养院大概一英里
There's a train station. It's about a mile from the home on Route 6.
这样好些吗？这样行不行？
Is this better? How's this?
你知道我喜欢那辆车
You know I love that car.
你最好希望他不会丢弃它
You better hope he doesn't trash it.
我不明白你干嘛不上周修好它
I don't see why you couldn't have done this weeks ago.
好吧！好吧
Yeah, yeah.
- 顺利吗？ - 签上去了
- Hey, did it go good?  - Yeah. I signed him in.
- 有人看到你吗？ - 没有
- Anyone see you?  - No.
现在是他们的事了
It's their problem now.
你来了，我正到处找你呢
Oh, there you are. I've been looking all over for you.
我们有个严重的问题
We have a serious problem.
卡萝，你在听吗？
Carol, are you listening?
特洛太太昨晚弄坏了监控器
Mrs. Tetlow vandalized her ankle monitor last night.
我想要你多留意她
I want you to pay special attention to her.
我担心她会伤到自己
I'm concerned. She might be a danger to herself.
好的，好极了
Okay, great.
- 好极了？ - 嗯
- Great?  - Um...
我会留意的，别担心
I'll take care of it. Don't worry.
你干嘛回来？
Why did you come back?
与你无关
Nobody's business.
你料到我不会叫警察
You knew I wouldn't call the cops on you,
但不表示我肯定会签你返院
but that doesn't mean I won't sign you up for bingo.
所以…
So...
你干嘛要回来？
Why did you come back?
好吧，我替你说
All right. I'll do it for you.
你在摆脱我之后
After making a complete ass of me,
想和什么人联系，但没联系上
you went and called someone, but you couldn't reach them.
不，也许你联系上了，他们会来接你
No. Maybe you did reach them, and they're gonna pick you up here.
你在这比在外面要安全得多…
I mean, you're a lot safer here than you are on the outside...
而且不会惊动警察，是吧？
with the cops looking for you, right?
也有可能…
Or maybe...
你回来是因为不想连累我
you came back because you didn't want to get me in trouble.
“N”四三
"N"43.
啊！
Ah.
你来了，曼宁先生
There you are, Mr. Manning.
- 他是说“B”一三吗？ - 不，亲爱的，是“G”
- Did they say "B" 13?  - No, dear, it was "G."
- 我觉得不是  - 我很确定，亲爱的，是“G”
- I don't think so.  - Oh, I'm quite sure of it, dear. It was "G."
- 我听到是“D”  - 我不想再争下去
- I heard "D."  - I don't want to argue about it anymore.
“G”，为了乔治
"G"for George.
- 你是说“B”一三？ - 要知道我真的不想再争论了
- Did you say "B" 13?  - I really don't want to argue about this, you know.
就是“G”
It was "G."
哦，看啊
Oh, look.
曼宁先生赢了
Mr. Manning has a bingo.
运气真好
Lucky man.
我找不到结婚戒指了
I can't find my weddin' ring.
别担心，亲爱的，会找到的
Oh, don't worry, dear. It'll turn up.
我一直把它藏在同一个地方的
I don't know. And I always hide it in the same place.
- 我肯定会找到的，亲爱的  - 我不知道
- Well, I'm sure it'll turn up, dear.  - I don't know.
- 你不用担心  - 我这些天很健忘
- You mustn't worry.  - I'm so forgetful these days.
- 不  - 我在哪都找不到它
- No.  - I couldn't find it anywhere.
我丢了很多这类东西
I've lost a lot of things like that,
而且我想不出到底是怎么回事
and I just can't figure out what happens to them.
- 哦，老天  - 我来帮你，坚持住
- Oh, my... Oh!  - Let me help you. Hold on a minute.
他的头撞到了地上
He's landed on his head.
- 他没死吧？ - 没，我想只是跌了一下
- Did he croak?  - No. I think he just got a little bit lazy.
他很快就会好的
He'll be all right now.
我只能说你非常幸运
Well, you lucked out. That's all I can say.
“我”非常幸运？不是“我们”吗？
I lucked out? How about we lucked out?
嗯！
Hmm.
你现在不再想离开这了吧？
So now you're just gonna lay off, right?
是不是？
Right?
卡萝，一切又回复了原样
Carol, everything's back where it was.
用不着再没事找事对吧？
Don't screw it up again, okay?
是的
Okay.
嘿！
Hey!
钱带来了吗？
Okay, got the money?
什么意思，你没带？
What do you mean, you didn't bring it?
狗娘养的，那你来这干什么？
You son of a bitch! What the hell are you doin' here?
嘿！
Hey!
啊！
Ahh!
嘘！
Shh.
我能帮什么忙吗？
Is there anything I can do?
有，攒够一百万，然后劫持一架飞机
Yeah. Scrape up a million bucks, then hijack a plane.
怎么回事？你的拍档带着你的钱跑了吗？
So what happened? Did your partner run out with your money?
我的拍档早死了
My partner's dead.
我在监狱时他设法和我取得过联系…
Before he went, I was in the slammer, and he got in touch...
他问我想怎么处理我的钱
and asked me what I wanted to do with my money.
我跟他说“让你儿子替我保管”
So I told him, "Let your kid hold it for me."
聪明的小子，我教会他怎么在牌戏中作弊
Cute kid. Taught him how to hustle gin rummy.
知道那小子刚才对我怎么说吗？
You know what that cute kid just told me?
如果我回来或者想干点什么，他会打发我一点
If I come around or try anything, he's gonna drop a dime.
我累坏了
Man, am I beat.
早上尽量别弄出声音
Try not to make noise in the morning.
你今天休息不是吗？
It's your day off, right?
是啊，可基蒂在搬家，我说过要帮她
Yeah, but Kitty's moving. I told her I'd help her.
那个吸血鬼
Well, that sucks.
我知道，可我欠她人情
I know, but I owe her a favor.
不能置之不理
I can't get out of it now.
你要戒烟？
Are you quitting?
想试试
Gonna try.
我看不懂这些说明
I can't understand these instructions.
亲爱的，我正在看这个
Honey, I'm trying to read this.
嘿，卡萝
Hey, Carol.
待会我要回来
I thought I'd come back later,
- 可以用我的大摩托载你一程  - 谢谢，卡尔
- give you a ride on my hog.  - That's good, Karl.
不过你的车我觉得称之为小摩托更恰当
But if you're gonna compare your crank to a bike, you should get a scooter.
我看不下去了
I can't look.
哦，亲爱的
Oh, dear.
我的天
Oh, my God.
没事，他爬起来了
It's okay. He's getting up.
坚持住
Hold on a minute.
不，他倒下了
No, he's out.
他会需要一个好牙医
He's gonna need a good dentist.
太过关心不是好事
It's a matter of getting too attached.
我知道，可他不象别人有亲人
I know, but it's just that he doesn't have family like the others.
我明白，但会很麻烦…
I understand, but it'll be that much harder...
当他们把他转回监狱医院时
when they transfer him back to a prison hospital.
什么时候？
When?
他们答应尽快安排床位
They promised me there'll be a bed opening up soon.
看你的样子我们是在去什么地方
You look like we're going someplace.
是个惊喜
It's a surprise.
- 那是戒烟贴吗？ - 嗯
- Is that a nicotine patch?  - Mm-hmm.
我可不想你再拿自己当烟灰缸
I didn't want you using yourself as an ashtray again.
谢谢
Thanks.
到了
Here you go.
- 短暂的逃脱  - 我不需要旅行散心
- Nice little getaway for you.  - I don't need a round trip.
有家银行
A bank.
谢谢
Thanks.
觉得怎么样？
So what do you think?
- 我该点薄烤饼的  - 我是指银行
- I should've ordered pancakes.  - I mean about the bank.
他们赠送免费烤面包机
What, they're giving away free toaster ovens.
你能想象哪种傻瓜…
Can you imagine what kind of moron it takes...
会为了免费烤面包机而去银行开户？
to open a bank account in order to get a free toaster oven?
- 你觉得我们能得手吗？ - 你说什么？
- Think we could knock that place off?  - Beg your pardon?
你觉得我们能得手吗？
Do you think we could knock that place off?
- 谁？ - 你和我
- Who?  - You and me.
亲爱的，我扮的是脑死亡而不是脑损伤
Honey, I am playing brain-dead, not brain-damaged.
说说看，你怎么能要求你照顾的死人…
Tell me, how can you go from just taking care of dead people...
听到这些话？
to what I'm listening to now?
- 是你说我该换个环境  - 什么时候？
- You're the one who said I needed a new town.  - When?
跳舞的时候…
When we were dancing...
你还说我和韦恩之间已经没有意义了
and you said me and Wayne didn't make sense anymore.
你想通过抢银行来挽救婚姻？干嘛不去找牧师？
You wanna save your marriage by robbing a bank. Why don't you go see a priest?
- 我不是这意思  - 那是什么意思？
- That's not what I'm saying.  - What are you saying?
我是说…
I'm saying...
我总会有老到动不了的一天
I'm gonna wake up one morning wearing diapers,
生活无法自理
sucking lime Jell-O through a straw,
我想知道我人生的去向
and I'm gonna wonder where my life went.
在这方面我才是个死人
I'm the one who's dead here.
我得…做点什么
I gotta... do something.
坚持跳膝上舞
Stick to lap dancing.
这儿没什么事吧？
Is everything okay here?
这儿没什么事
Yeah, everything's okay here.
外面就难说了
I'm not so sure about out there.
- 嗨  - 嗨
- Hi.  - Hi.
我想要台烤面包机
Um, I want a toaster oven.
好极了，我们来办一个开户申请
Great. Let's just get you a new-account application.
不，我不想开新帐户
Oh, no, no. I don't want to open a new account.
我只想要烤面包机
I just want a toaster oven.
是这样的
Oh, well, that's the thing, see.
你得先开个新帐户，最低限度五百美元
First, you have to open up a new account, $500 minimum,
然后才能拿到烤面包机
and then you get a toaster oven.
“华维尔”
"Farwell."
- 能叫你华维尔吗？ - 当然
- Can I call you Farwell?  - Please.
你知道吗？
You know something?
- 我曾经是舞会皇后  - 是吗？
- I used to be the prom queen.  - Really?
- 我一点不奇怪  - 但可悲的是…
- I'm not surprised.  - But the sad fact is,
“舞会皇后”并不是终身保障
prom queen, it doesn't really prepare you for much in life.
从那之后就每况愈下
It's been kind of downhill ever since.
我不是在诉苦，我是说我已经风光不再
I'm not saying I'm bitter. I'm just saying that I don't have much time.
现在只有一样东西能恢复我对自己的良好感觉
And there's only one thing that's gonna make me feel good about myself again.
烤面包机
Toast.
我感觉有点糊涂了
Uh, I'm afraid I don't understand.
- 那就给我一台烤面包机  - 抱歉，我…
- Then give me a toaster oven.  - Sorry, ma'am, l...
我不想给你找不痛快，华维尔
I don't wanna have to get ugly on you, Farwell.
快走
Hurry.
老天，我需要来支烟
God, I need a cigarette.
想知道说明书的内容吗？
Wonder if they have this in black?
“马铃薯，四百五十度烘烤四十五分钟”
"Baked potatoes, 450 degrees for 45 minutes."
你就是这样打银行主意的？
That's your idea of a bank job, huh?
“中等罐装糕饼…”
"Cakes in medium tins..."
你晃晃胸脯就弄到了一台烤面包机
Hey, you flashed your knockers, you got a toaster.
“三百五十度烘烤三十分钟”
"350 degrees for 30 minutes."
要是脱掉裤子也许能弄台铸铁炉
If you'd have dropped your panties, you might have got a cast-iron stove.
“解冻后的糕饼…”
"And defrosted pastries..."
没准是一整套厨具，我的天
Who knows? A whole kitchen, for Christ's sake.
“三百二十五度，十五分钟”
"15 minutes at 325."
怎么了
Excuse me.
你兴奋过头了
You're up.
这大概就是你那见鬼的银行抢劫
Here's what I think of your goddamn bank robbery.
这上面说它不能用水浸泡
It says you're not supposed to immerse it in water.
你没认真听我说
Hey, you ain't listenin'.
我说的是，不管看起来多容易，总会有工作要做
What I'm sayin' is, however easy it looks, you got a job to do.
什么意思？
Meaning?
要做好功课
Do your homework.
啊！
Ah.
嘿！
Hey.
搬家的事怎么样？
Hey. How was the move?
累得要死
It was a pain in the ass.
小心把衣服弄脏
Hey, you know what? You're gonna get grease on your clothes.
- 出了什么事吗？ - 没有
- Something wrong?  - No.
你应该看看，他们就象采集花粉的蜜蜂
You should've seen it. They looked like bees coming to gather up pollen,
我跟着他们找到了蜂房
so I followed them back to the hive.
一个存放处，银行的银行的所在地
A depository, Henry, where the banks bank.
方圆一百英里只此一家
The only one around for a hundred miles.
有很多的蜂蜜，亲爱的
That's a lot of honey, honey.
功课做得还行吗？
How's that for homework?
钱的数目和难度是成正比的
Good on the money, not so good on the choice.
五年前两个人也许行，现在则需要一支军队
Five years ago, maybe, but today you'd need an army.
可以在送达之前袭击押款车
We hit the armored car, get the money before it gets in.
我肯定快疯了
I must be goin' nuts.
- 就两个人而言还是会很困难  - 嗯
- It'd be tough with two.  - Hmm.
亲爱的，是我，我还在基蒂这儿
Hi,honey, it's me. I'm still with Kitty.
我会晚点回家，好吗？
Um, I'll be home a little later, okay?
哇哦！
Whoa! Whoa!
韦恩，你这是要去哪？
Hey, Wayne, where do you think you're going?
- 你没事吧，伙计？ - 没事
- You all right there, buddy?  - Yep.
只是问问
Just checking.
顺便提醒那边有个停车标志
By the way, that was a stop sign back there.
是吗？
Oh, yeah?
- 代我向卡萝问好  - 好的
- Okay. Say hi to Carol.  - Yep.
- 嗨！ - 嗨，基蒂
- Hi.  - Hi, Kitty.
你好
Lady.
我已经受够了
I've had enough of this.
艾玛，替我照看一下狄娅娜
Irma, take Diane for me for a minute.
- 不  - 我会还你个人情
- No!  - Please? I'll owe you one.
- 真的？ - 去吧
- One?  - Just do it.
见鬼
Come on.
韦恩，我们要干什么？
Wayne, what are we doin'?
我倒想知道你想对我老婆干什么
I'd like to know what you think you're doing with my wife.
离她远点，不然我要你好看
You stay away from her. I'll clean your clock.
从现在起，你要是知趣的话，她给你的只有药
From now on, if you know what's good for you, she gives you your medicine,
从你这拿走的只有体温计，就这些
she takes your temperature and that's it.
韦恩，你想干嘛？你不能在这乱来
Wayne, what are you doing? What are you doing? You can't do this here!
我想怎样就能怎样
Why not? I can do whatever the hell I want!
- 你会把一切都搞砸  - 我会把一切搞砸？
- Shh! You're gonna blow everything.  - I'm gonna blow everything?
你们那天在车上是怎么回事？
What about you, the other day in your damn car?
- 别想撒谎，我看到你们了  - 嘘！
- Don't bother lying. I saw you.  - Shh!
我们得谈谈
We have to talk.
事情不是你想的那样
It's not what you think, if that's what you're thinking.
- 你倒说说看  - 好吧
- Tell me about it.  - Okay.
- 我们在一起办事  - 你说什么？
- We're working together.  - What are you talking about?
我们在一起干一件事
We're doing a job together.
- 什么事？ - 一件银行的事
- What job?  - A bank job.
你指望我能相信这话？
You expect me to believe that?
- 当然  - 你是说你并不想勾搭这老家伙
- Yes.  - Okay, so you don't want to screw the old guy.
只是想和他去抢银行
You just want to rob a bank with him.
不，是抢押款车
No. It's just an armored car.
哦，只是辆装有钢板…
Oh. Just one of those steel-plated trucks,
防弹玻璃，里边有人拿着枪的车子？
bulletproof glass, a couple guys inside with shotguns, Carol?
事实上我们就是因此才想要你加入
That's exactly why we were gonna ask you to do it with us,
- 但你没给过我们机会  - “我们”？你什么意思？“我们”？
- but you didn't give us a chance.  - Us? What do you mean, us?
- 我和亨利  - 卡萝，我们才是我们，他是他
- Me and Henry.  - Carol, we're us. He's just him.
- 亲爱的…  - 我要告诉那杂种…
- Honey...  - I'm gonna tell that son of a bitch...
不，这是我的主意
No! It was my idea.
是吗？在他来之前你可从没想过要抢银行
Yeah? Well, you never wanted to rob a bank until he came along.
- 亨利，你来这干嘛？ - 看好病人…
- Henry, what are you doing here?  - How am I gonna run the sprinklers...
- 你这样让我怎么工作？ - 我不知道，妈的
- when you leave your people all over the place?  - I don't know. Shoot!
谢谢，伙计
Thanks, man.
我就猜到你会来这
Figured you'd be here.
- 为什么你不能只是个购物狂呢？ - 回家吧
- How come you couldn't just be a compulsive shopper?  - Let's go home.
- 那我还能应付  - 回家吧
- I can deal with that.  - Let's go home.
看着点
Watch it.
知道我得出的结论吗？
You know the conclusion I've come to?
我的想法无足轻重
It doesn't matter what I think.
而你想到了什么你就非做不可
You get something in your head, you're gonna do it.
没错吧？
Right?
我该怎么做？把你捆在树上…
What am I gonna do, tie you to a tree or...
还是等你想明白了自己放弃？
have you put away till you get your head straightened out?
告诉你我会怎么做
I'll tell you what I'm gonna do.
我要加入你们
I'm gonna do it with you.
真的？
You are?
一点不错，真的
You're damn right, I am.
- 太好了，正好…  - 不，等等
- That's great. That's exactly...  - No, no. Hold on.
不是因为你要求我才加入
I'm not doing it 'cause you want me to.
而是因为我想干，懂吗？
I'm doing it 'cause I want to, okay?
还有，如果我加入，你要听我的而不是他的
And another thing. If I'm in, you listen to me, not him.
还有…
And...
事情过后
After this,
我们就要恢复原样，行吗？
we can go back to normal, right?
不能有下一回
No... No more robberies.
你同意吗？
You got it?
同意
Got it.
你说过可以加一个人
You said we could use a third.
没有，我是说两个人干会很困难
No, I didn't. I said it would be tough with two.
你没见过他打橄榄球
You should've seen him on the football field.
他很有控制能力
He was so clutch.
也很理智
He always kept his head.
他昨天就失去理智了
He didn't keep his head yesterday.
有什么奇怪？他看到我们一起在车上
What did you expect? He saw us in the car together.
我骗了他，他当然会光火
I lied to him. Of course he went nuts.
如果反过来呢？
I mean, what if it were reversed?
如果换了你是他的话？
What if it were you and me?
你会把他在轮椅上撂倒…
You would've flattened him right in his wheelchair...
在电视室当着所有小老太太的面
in the TV room, in front of all the little old ladies.
你该相信他的自控能力
You should give Wayne some credit for self-control.
- 嘿，别再说了  - 那好
- Hey, don't push it.  - Okay.
这样吧，要么他加入要么我退出
Try this. Either he's in or I'm out.
真是外行当家
Ohh! Amateur hour.
要是有人跟我说，一对半吊子夫妻作主…
If anybody had ever told me a husband and wife amateur hour...
先说好了，如果有任何闪失，我会掉头就走
But one thing clear. If anything goes sour, I'm gone.
我会瞅准机会抢些零钱
I will take my chances, rifle the soda machine,
跳上该死的计程车，明白吗？
take a goddamn cab, you got that?
明白
Got it.
加油站
Gas station.
R.B超市
Oh, Rite Buy supermarket.
十五条结帐通道，二十四小时营业
Fifteen checkout lanes, open twenty-four hours a day.
你算算看
You do the math.
加油站
Gas station.
下一家归我
Oh, this next one's mine.
是那家体育酒吧，他们有所有的体育频道
That's that sports bar where they got all the sports channels.
没错，可没人会在那花一分钱
Yeah, but nobody spends any money in there.
至少它不是加油站
Hey, well, at least it's not a gas station.
加油要付现金，亲爱的，这主意不赖
People pay cash for gas, honey. It's a good idea.
拍得不错，两位，但你们弄错了
Hey, it's a nice show, guys, but you got it backwards.
要抢的不是押运线路，而是抢押运队
You don't rob the route. You rob the crew.
一旦看到押送员…
When you see a pair of Boy Scouts...
巡视时手不离枪套，就离远点
marching around with their hands in their holsters, just stay away.
你们要找的是真正的笨蛋
What you're looking for is a couple of real oafs.
嘿，宝贝，你好吗？
Hey, baby, how you doin'?
嗨！
Hi.
看到没？她冲我笑呢
You see that? She smiled at me.
告诉你，女人都离不了我
I'm tellin'ya, women never leave me alone.
你是说他们都离开了押款车？
You mean they were both out of the truck?
发财了
Bingo.
- 在移交结束时下手
So we hit these guys at the end of their shift,
- 是最佳时机对吧？ - 不
- we're golden, right?  - No.
但这计划很完美，那是些白痴
But it's perfect. These guys are idiots.
他们运送的钱越多，拔枪的速度就越快
The more money they're carrying, the quicker their fingers will be on the trigger.
在接运开始前动手
We take it with the beginning of the shift,
- 他们的警惕性会较低  - 可车上也是空的
- when they're really not paying attention.  - Truck's gonna be empty.
然后我们能取而代之不是吗？
We have our work cut out for us then, don't we?
我想我们应该…
I think we should...
为女士们安排一次野餐
have a little picnic for the ladies.
这样我们接你出去时就顺理成章
So the times we took you out won't seem so suspicious.
- 全中  - 我也全程参与，行吗？
- Bingo too.  - Uh, I'm gonna sit this one out, okay?
哇哦！
Whoo!
九点九分
9.9!
- 九分  - 五分
- Nine.  - Five.
- 嗯？ - 你没有保持双腿并拢
- Huh?  - You didn't keep your feet together!
- 我有  - 你肯定没有
- I did too!  - You certainly did not!
不，我有
Yes, I did!
化妆道具，胶带，都写在单子上了
Makeup stuff, duct tape. It's all on the list.
你去找一个叫刘易斯的
I want you to get in touch with a guy by the name of Lewis.
是我的朋友
He's a friend of mine.
- 好的  - 由他去弄枪，电话在上边
- Okay.  - He'll get the gun guys. Number is right there. That's it.
嘿，韦恩
Hey, Wayne.
和他们打交道要镇定
Be cool with these guys, huh?
我明白
I got it.
要看着他们的眼睛
Look 'em in the eye,
但不象是为了记住他们的相貌
but not like you're gonna remember their faces.
你觉得能做到吗？
You think you can do that?
没问题
No problem.
你肯定就是在这？
Are you sure this is the place?
他是这么说的
Yeah. That's what he told me.
你准备好了？
Are you up for this?
当然，我能应付
Hmm? Oh, yeah. I can handle it.
这样行吗？
How's this?
眼不要眯那么厉害
Don't squint so much.
好的
Right, okay.
钥匙留在点火器上，关好门
Leave the key in the ignition. Lock the door.
嘿！
Hey.
- 小心点  - 我会的
- Be careful.  - I will.
要来支烟吗？
Got a cigarette?
我戒了
Uh, I quit.
钱带来了吗？
You got the money?
哦，是的，嗯…
Oh, yeah. Um...
- 走吧  - 去哪？
- Well, let's go.  - Where to?
你到底想不想交易？
You don't really wanna do this now, do ya?
不…我是说，是的
No... I mean, yeah.
- 那走吧  - 走吧
- Let's just do it.  - All right, come on. Let's go.
哦，上帝
Oh, my God.
老天
Jesus!
交易完了，走吧
It's a done deal. Let's go.
要我说韦恩干得很不错
I'm supposed to tell you Wayne did fine.
我听说了，他差点没弄脏裤子
The way I heard it, he just barely didn't soil his shorts.
- 对，可他毕竟控制住了  - 哦
- Yeah, well, he's still clutch.  - Ah.
- 周一晚查过房后见  - 就这样？
- See you Monday night after bed check.  - That's it?
对，就这样
Yeah, that's it.
我猜也就这样了
I guess that's it.
- 嘿  - 嘿！
- Hey.  - Hey.
偷来的车
Grand theft auto.
现在我们真正走上邪道了
We are now officially on the wrong path.
- 我们得做准备了  - 就一会
- We have to get ready.  - Just a second.
啊！
Ah!
大家感觉怎么样？
So, how is everybody?
很好，很好
Pretty good. Uh, pretty good.
你干什么？
What are you doing?
你不想看看她怎么样吗？
You gonna see if she's okay?
噢
Oh.
也许我…
Oh, yeah. Maybe I, uh...
亲爱的？
Honey?
见鬼的戒烟贴
Goddamn nicotine patches.
继续上路
Let's get going.
我得在五小时内回到床上
In five hours, I gotta be back in my little bed.
- 只要放上花生黄油就行  - 它们会上钩？
- You put a little peanut butter on the trap, that's all.  - And they go for it?
- 它们知道奶酪…  - 别乱动
- Cheese they know about 'cause...  - Drop everything.
手放到车上
Hands on the truck.
照他说的做，去车上把门打开
You heard the man. Get in the van. Get that door open.
走吧
Let's go.
上去
Go on. Get up.
- 进展顺利  - 很好，我们得保持进度
- Right on schedule.  - Good. We gotta stay that way.
一旦延后就大事不妙了
We get behind, the alarms start popping.
早，我们是钱伯斯递运服务公司
Good morning. This is Chambers Courier Service.
通常为你们服务的押款车出了机械故障
We're experiencing some mechanical problems with your usual truck.
我们会按预定时间另外派人来接收
We're gonna reroute another crew to make your scheduled pickup.
我们会在马克市场作好准备
We're all set at the Max Mart.
我们将在九分钟内赶到
We've gotta be there in nine minutes.
掉个头，我很快就回来
Turn her around. I won't be long.
有辆该死的警车
There's a damn cop car out here.
我们怎么办？
What do we do?
- 他们肯定在里面  - 只管到前面等着
- They must be inside.  - Just go in front and wait, I guess.
你以前是警察？
You an ex-cop?
我管过食品安全
I used to be in food security.
象细菌，蛋白质保护功能之类的
You know, bacterial stuff, protein protection.
我小弟弟在马里兰当过警察
My kid brother used to be a trooper in Maryland.
- 那是个好地方  - 对，那儿不错
- Nice state, Maryland.  - Yeah, it's a nice state.
回见，伙计们，我还得忙
I'll see you guys. Boy, I got a long night.
嘿，你认识一个叫费萨诺的司机吗？
Hey! You know a guy named Fassano, drives for Trusty?
费萨诺
Fassano.
- 我认识的叫帕萨诺  - 不是他
- Passano. I know a Passano.  - Not him.
他是个好人，是我的同事
No, no. He is a good guy. He's a member of my flock.
要知道白天我得去教堂
You see, my day job, I got this church.
问你们点事
Let me ask you guys something.
你们有没有蒙受神恩？
Are you guys in a state of grace?
- 神恩？ - 对
- Grace?  - Yeah.
你们是在与主同行，还是觉得有可能…
Are you running parallel with the Lord right now, or do you think maybe,
有可能你们已经误入歧途？
just maybe you're runnin' down a wrong-way street?
是在叫我们吗？
Is that our radio?
- 对，应该是  - 我们得走了
- Yeah, I think so.  - Gotta go.
祝你愉快，小心点
Have a good night. Take care.
彼此
Peace.
我们晚了三分钟
We're three minutes behind.
我是钱伯斯递运的狄娜
Hi, this is Deena at Chambers Courier.
通常前往你处接运的人员出了些状况
The guys who normally pick you up,
我们已经另外派人过来
We're sending a couple of new guys over.
他们在体育场等我们，大概要到音乐会结束之后
Hey, guys, they're ready for us at the stadium. Guess the concert's over.
我还行吗？
Am I good?
还行
You're good.
- 你好  - 坐好了吗？ - 走吧
- Hiya. Good.  - How's it going? Good.
- 谢谢各位  - 不客气
- Thank you, guys.  - You're welcome.
好了，我们走
Okay, sweetie, let's hit the road.
一万两千个座位，每座三十块，一共三十六万
Okay, 12,000 seats, 30 bucks a seat, 360 grand.
外加其他消费六万
Plus your beer or whatnot. Add another 60.
总计四十二万
420 thou, exactly.
没错，花四十二万来看什么？
That's right. 420,000. And for what?
两个人拿着麦克风乱蹦乱跳，念念有词
The two of them bouncing around with a microphone, talking. Talking!
- 那也叫音乐？ - 不，不
- Is that music? Huh?  - No. No!
我英语不行，但写的东西也比那要好
I flunked English, but I can write better stuff than that.
懂我意思吗？另一个傻瓜则在刮唱片
You know what I'm sayin'? Then they got this other bozo up there scratching records.
一晚四十二万就为了看这些
That's it. 420 thou for one night.
你要挣四十二万得花多长时间？算算看
How long would it take you to make 420 grand, huh? Figure it out.
不知道，五乘五，是二…
I don't know. Five times five, carry your two...
是二十年，如果你资历够深的话
Twenty years, that's how long, if you've got seniority.
想知道更让人沮丧的是什么吗？
But you wanna know what makes it worse?
想知道吗？
You wanna know?
他们每晚都能挣那么多
They make that much every night out.
没错
Yep.
看看那
Look at that.
- 没人会说人生就是一碗樱桃  - 是啊
- Well, nobody said life was a bowl of cherries.  - Yeah.
哇！
Wow.
- 晚安  - 晚安
- Yeah. Good night.  - Nightie-night.
我是“钱伯斯递运”的狄娜
Hi, this is Deena at Chambers Courier.
我们今天晚了一点
We're running a little bit late today.
我们在这条线路上安排是新面孔
Yeah, we've got some new guys on the route.
原因我们已经说过
Yeah, you know how it is.
哟!
Yo!
- 新来的？ - 对，你是肯尼？
- You're new?  - That's me. You Kenny?
对，肯尼二世
Mm-hmm. Kenny Jr.
哦，是家族生意对吧？
Oh. It's a family business, huh?
对，我们是他妹妹
Yeah, we're his sisters.
不要提我妹妹
Don't be talking about my sister.
我马上回来
I'll be right back.
你们糟了，他去跟妈妈告状了
You in a lot of trouble. He gonna tell his mommy.
待会想跟我去转转吗？
Y'all gonna be around when I get off?
带着几口袋的钱，要我们去哪都行
Um, bring a couple bags of money, we'll be wherever you want us to be.
一言为定，一个钟头后见
You got yourself a deal. About an hour.
我是钱伯斯递运的狄娜，早上好
Hi, this is Deena at Chambers Courier. Good morning.
对，是钱伯斯递运公司，我们今天晚了一点
Yes, this is Chambers Courier Service. We're running a little bit late today.
通常来你处接运的车辆出了点状况
The guys who normally pick you up, well, they threw a rod over at the AM-PM.
我们要另外派人来接运
We're gonna reroute another crew to make your scheduled pickup.
我们已经另派了一组人过来，谢谢
We're sending a couple of new guys over. That's right. Great. Thanks. Thank you.
最后一站
Last stop coming up.
- 时间  - 差不多刚刚好
- Time.  - We're just about caught up.
跟我三天前来时不一样，当时大门没关
This isn't how it was three days ago when I was here. The gate wasn't closed.
- 也许我们该放弃这一家  - 掉头离去吗？
- Maybe we should forget about this one.  - Make a U-turn?
警卫会马上报警，开进去
The guard'll be on the phone to the dispatcher right away. Go on in.
- 你好吗？ - 还不赖
- How're you doin'?  - Not bad.
可真不少
Big haul.
是啊
Yeah.
- 请你在这上边签个字  - 好的，先生
- Why don't you just put your John Hancock on this.  - All right, sir.
那箱子通不过传送槽，它太大了
That box won't fit in the chute. It's too big.
老天
Oh, man.
你得打开门搬上去
You load it up in the back of the truck.
- 那不合规定  - 我们得想点办法
- That's against regulation.  - We have to do something.
- 是啊，但现在都这样干  - 嗯
- Yeah, but that's the way we do it now.  - Uh-huh.
我是新来的，他们什么都没告诉我
Well, I'm new on this run, and they don't tell me nothin'.
- 你可以打个电话证实一下  - 不用
- Why don't you give a buzz and clear it up?  - No!
好吧，我…
That's okay. L...
- 来…  - 不，我来吧
- Here...  - No, I got it.
- 老天  - 我知道会派新面孔来
- Oh, man.  - Told me they were sending in a new guy,
可你看起来干过这行
but you look like you've been doin' this a while.
- 见鬼  - 我已经退休了
- Oh, man.  - I'm ready for retirement.
- 不能让他看到你  - 我知道
- You can't let him see you.  - I know.
没人会雇用超过五十岁的人
But nobody's gonna hire you over 50.
问题是，大家没意识到五十岁出头…
The thing is, what people don't realize is after 50...
是雇员的最佳年龄
is the best time to hire a man.
有养老保障，升职加薪都毋须考虑他们
His oats are sown, all the hell-raising is out of his system.
Hey. What is that? Is that a phone?
什么声音？是电话响吗？
你最好去接一下
You better get that.
- 我敢说是你的老婆子  - 你看…
- I bet you that's your old lady.  - Yeah, look...
你能应付这个吗？
You gonna be all right with this?
- 没问题  - 我很快就来
- Oh, you bet.  - I'll be right back.
嗨，我是钱伯斯递运的狄娜
Hi, this is Deena from Chambers Courier again.
电话里说是你的老婆子
Hey, the dispatcher says it's your old lady.
她要你带点牛奶回去
She wants you to pick up some milk.
我在哪她都能找到
She can find me anyplace.
没错，祝你愉快
Yeah, look, have a nice day.
太酷了，真他妈的酷
That was so cool. Damn, was that cool.
我是说，真他妈的酷
I mean, that was so damn cool. Damn.
- 一点不错  - 没错，正是如此
- You nailed it.  - That's right. All the way.
我有个朋友住在弗罗里达，是养赛狗的
I had this buddy down in Florida, bred greyhounds.
他有条小狗
He had this one pup.
这种狗肯定要跑得越快越好
Dog just finally went faster and faster and faster.
有天晚上在直道上
And one night on the backstretch,
那条狗逮到一只机器兔子
that dog caught up with a mechanical rabbit.
咬了一嘴金属，二百二十伏的电压，一下就被击倒
Took a mouthful of metal, 220 volts and dropped like a stone.
它得到了想要的，但结果却让它大失所望
Well, I guess he got what he wanted, but it sure wasn't what he expected.
它逮到了兔子是吧？
He caught the rabbit, didn't he?
- 对，它逮到了兔子  - 真是令人沮丧
- Oh, yeah, he got the rabbit.  - What a bummer.
想象一下，那一刻…等等
Just imagine. The moment... Wait a minute.
活见鬼
What the hell.
不，不，是怎么回事？
Oh, no. No! How did this happen?
他们都被我捆住了，捆得很紧
I tied 'em up. That's all I know. I tied 'em up good.
- 不，我的天  - 韦恩
- Oh, no. Man.  - Wayne!
- 你去哪？ - 我得去找他们
- Where are you going?  - Well, I gotta look for them.
得了，浪费时间，他们可能在任何地方
Aw, come on. Waste of time. They could be anywhere.
最近的公路有多远？
How far is the nearest road?
八九英里，你该知道
I don't know. Eight or nine miles. You rode in with me. You tell me.
幸运的话，我们还有一个钟头，把东西卸下来
If we're lucky, we got an hour before they get to a phone. Let's get this thing unloaded.
我明明把他们捆得很紧
I tied 'em up. I tied 'em up good.
这是你的吗？
Is this yours?
我们先离开这
Let's get out of these outfits.
找东西装好袋子转到“野马”车上
Grab the bags with the big stuff. Transfer them in the Mustang.
把我送到疗养院然后把钱藏好，韦恩
Drop me off at the home and then stash the dough at your place. Wayne.
这辆车扔到机场附近，让他们以为我们上飞机了
Ditch the van near the airport. Make 'em think maybe we're taking a plane.
- 韦恩？ - 好的，好的
- Wayne?  - Yeah, yeah.
打电话那招很漂亮
That was nice work on the phone back there.
谢谢
Thanks.
- 一路顺风  - 保重
- Nice going.  - Be careful.
早上好，亨利
Good morning, Henry.
睡得还好吗？
Did we have a good sleep?
知道吗…？
You know what?
妈的
Damn it.
肯定是从我口袋里滑落的
It had to fall out of my pocket.
别担心，我们不会有事
Don't worry about it. We're gonna be okay.
- 我就是放在口袋里的  - 我知道
- Yeah, 'cause that's where I put it.  - I know.
- 我放在口袋里了  - 我知道
- That's where I goddamn put it.  - I know.
左，收脚，一，二，三
And left, kick in. One, two, three.
右，收脚，做得好，狄娅娜
And right, in. Good, Diane.
左，收脚，一，二，三
And left, in. One, two, three.
右，收脚，一，二，三
And right, in. One, two, three.
- 啊！ - 对不起
- Ah!  - Sorry.
有消息来源估计被劫金额达两百万美元
But sources estimate the amount of money stolen at two million dollars.
警方声称已掌握有关劫匪身份的线索
Police say they have a number of leads as to the identities of the robbers.
- 亨利  - 基蒂
- Henry.  - Kitty!
- 怎么？ - 威勒太太…
- Yeah?  - Mrs. Weiler.
- 找我  - 正是
- Wants me.  - You got it.
扶住他，坐好，亨利
You gotta hold him. Sit up, Henry.
刚在新闻上看到他们在机场找到了那辆车
I just heard it on the news. They found the van at the airport.
他们在寻找两个今早飞往迈阿密的家伙
They're looking for two guys who flew to Miami this morning.
喂？
Hello?
对，我知道，我知道，我听过广播
Yeah. I know, I know. I heard.
是啊，我们脱身了，再见
Yeah. We're home free. Bye.
出什么事了？
What's going on?
明天见
See you tomorrow.
我们来接他，谢谢你们对他的照顾
We'll take it from here. Thank you for taking care of him.
- 可怜的家伙  - 我们得想想办法
- Poor guy.  - We have to do something.
可我们能做什么呢？
Look, I'm sorry, but what can we do?
我们不能让他回那，得想点办法
We can't let him go back there. We have to do something.
我们除了表示遗憾也帮不上什么忙
No, wait. Now, listen. There's nothing else we can do.
- 我们得想办法  - 不，卡萝，先回家再说
- We have to do something.  - No, Carol. Just come home.
我的天
Aw, jeez.
嘿，小姐
Hey, lady.
小姐，你没事吧？
Lady, you all right?
- 我在找个朋友  - 啊哈，是我的女孩
- I'm looking for a friend of mine.  - Boy, that's my girl.
开门，快
Open it up. Do it!
- 还好吗，亨利？ - 怎么拖了这么久？
- How're you doin', Henry?  - What took you so long?
- 哦，老天  - 他昏迷时表现要好得多是吧？
- Aw, man.  - He's much nicer when he's in a coma, isn't he?
你干嘛这样做？你倒是说说看？你…
Why would you do this? Can't you just tell me why? You have no idea...
我说过要你回家的
I told you to come home!
把钱装好，我们在路上
Just get the money together. We're on our way.
你到底知不知道自己刚刚做过什么？
Do you have any idea what you just did? Do you?
你到底有没有脑子？
Carol, when are you ever gonna start using your head?
啊！
Ah!
你打算去哪？
Where you gonna go?
也许去北部呆一阵子
North, probably, for a while.
比较近
It's close.
然后去个暖和点的地方
Then, I don't know. Somewhere where it's warm.
你呢？
What about you?
不知道
I don't know.
我从没去过别的地方
I've never been anywhere else.
对不起，你做得对
I'm sorry. It's okay. You did the right thing.
很抱歉，我不该斥责你
I'm sorry I, uh, came down on you.
我收拾了一大堆衣物，不知道是否…
T-shirts. I got a bunch of stuff packed. Oh, and socks. I don't know if I...
我把钱分成了两份，这里和露营背包里…
I got the money split two ways... here and the duffel bag in there.
我能在这帮点小忙，我知道
I could use a little help here, Carol. I got it.
路上可以用，我们必须抓紧时间，所以…
This is just for the road. Lfigured we're really gonna have to make time, so...
我们得带上这些，没必要浪费
We're gonna have to take this stuff with us, otherwise, it's gonna go to waste.
我们什么都不能买，可以带上这些，不是吗？
Anything we can't buy, we can take with us, right?
- 什么？ - 我们现在有钱了，不在乎这些
- What?  - Well, we can afford it now. We got the money.
你想要杯咖啡吗？
Can I get you a cup of coffee?
哦，芥末，好的
Oh. Mustard, right, right.
你可以说该分成三份，但我不这么想
Okay. You could argue it's a three-way split, but I figure what the hell.
我和卡萝只拿一份，钱不过是身外之物
Me and Carol make one. After all, it's just money,
不如留点好处给你，不是吗？
Might as well throw you a little bone, right?
你是为你和卡萝达成的交易…
Did you make a deal for Carol too,
还是纯粹为了自己？
or just for yourself?
警察就在外面
Cops out there.
我是为我们才这样做
I did it for us.
是为了我们，罗…
I did it for us. L...
罗伊德说他们关心的不是我们，而是他
Lloyd-Lloyd said they didn't care about you and me. Just him.
总得有人背黑锅不是吗？
Somebody's gotta pay, right?
我能怎么样？我说过要你离他远点
What am I supposed to do? I told you to stay away from this guy.
你必须撇开他，我已经谈好条件…
You gotta stay away from him. I had this worked out...
我们可以从轻处罚
where we're just gonna get a slap on the wrist.
鉴于她劫了囚车，她的处罚会重一点
Only they're gonna slap her a little bit harder, seeing as she sprung me.
这就是所谓的“控制能力”？
That's the guy you call "clutch," huh?
好吧，废话说够了
All right, that's enough of this crap.
我们出去吧
We're going outside.
我哪都不去
I'm not going anywhere.
怎么了？
What?
- 我不会走  - 我警告你，卡萝
- I'm not going.  - I'm warning you, Carol.
你最好想明白
You'd better think about this.
我想好了
I have.
好吧，看来你是想要我帮你脱身
Okay. So you want me to make you go.
告诉你，这次我不干
Tell you what. This time I'm not gonna.
你怎么看？我们陷入绝境了吗？
So, what do you say? We go down in a blaze of glory?
我不知道什么“绝境”
I don't know about "glory,"
但我们肯定要面临险境了
but we're gonna go down in a blaze of something.
- 我…  - 好了，韦恩，把手背过去
- Uh, I...  - Okay, Wayne. Put your hands behind your back.
- 什么？ - 把手背过去
- What?  - Put your hands behind your back.
- 你干什么？ - 逮捕你
- What are you doing, Lloyd?  - I'm arresting you.
老天，别这样
Lloyd, Jesus. Come on.
把手放在头上慢慢走出来
Come out slowly with your hands above your heads.
你不曾有过生活…
You haven't lived...
在你听到那句话之前
till you've heard someone say that to you.
没事，我们控制了局面
Okay, all right. We've got a situation here.
该死的
Goddamn it! Oh, man.
去河边
The river!
- 别碰我  - 快到该死的车上去
- Get your hands off of me!  - Get in the goddamn car!
- 你不向我宣读我的权利？ - 不，夫人，你不是嫌犯
- Aren't you supposed to read me my rights?  - No, ma'am, you're not a suspect.
你不用向我宣读权利？
Yeah, but... aren't you supposed to read me my rights?
去年她有次违章驾驶被我们抓到…
Yeah, we got a moving violation on her last year...
在限速区超速…
fifty in a thirty-five zone...
没有接受处罚并有多次违章停车纪录
failure to complete traffic school and multiple outstanding parking violations.
他很有教养
He has good breeding.
从他的举止看得出来
How do I know? His bearing.
一个人的举止能说明很多事情
You can tell a lot about people by their bearing.
有点难以接受，但我猜是他拿了我的表
I kinda hate to admit it, but I think he got my watch.
女士们，拜托了，这是犯罪现场
Ladies, please. This is a crime scene.
- 你在开玩笑  - 他们毁掉了一个年轻护士的前途
- You're kidding me.  - They've ruined the career of a promising young nurse.
卡萝本来大有前途的
Carol Ann McKay had a future.
不是开玩笑？
You're not kidding?
需要效劳吗？
May I help?
我以前从没把它取下来过
It's just that I've never taken it off before.
哦，啧，啧，啧，确实太紧了
Oh. Tsk, tsk, tsk. It's completely stuck.
我知道，所以我才来这，你能帮忙吗？
Yes, I know. That's why I'm here. Can you help me?
我的助手要一小时后回来
My assistant is due back in an hour.
你到时候再来我们可以去后边弄断它
Why don't you return then and we'll go in the back and cut it off?
不能现在就想办法吗？
Oh, well, couldn't we just do it now?
你自己也行对吧？
I mean, you could do it yourself, right?
我离开就没人看店了
I can't leave the front unattended.
安全系统今早出了毛病
The security system's on the blink since this morning.
- 还没找出原因  - 明白了
- They can't figure out what happened.  - I see.
是我运气不好
Just my luck.
不过我下了很大决心才这样做而且…
It's just that I finally got the courage to do this and...
那是我人生的一段重要经历
I mean, it was a huge chunk of my life.
- 大学时的爱人？ - 高中
- College sweetheart?  - High school.
我从没结识过其他男人，你想想看
I've never even been with another man. Imagine that.
求你帮帮忙
Oh, please, just take it off.
来吧，跟我去后边
Come on. Come with me in the back.
会办妥的，我先把门关上
We'll be fine. I'll just lock the door.
你真是个好人
You're such a sweet man.
他…他不会有事吧？
Is, uh... Is he gonna be all right?
我爸爸不会有事
Daddy'll be fine.
我真希望能在他中风之前就…这样做
I just wish I could've done this before the... stroke.
但不管怎样，我相信在他内心深处会知道
But somehow, deep down, I think he'll know.
♪ You're always dancing down the street ♪
♪ With your suede blue eyes ♪
♪ And every new boy that you meet ♪
♪ Doesn't know the real surprise ♪
♪ Here she comes again ♪
♪ When she's dancing 'neath the starry sky ♪
♪ Ooh, she'll make you flip ♪
♪ Here she comes again ♪
♪ When she's dancing 'neath the starry sky ♪
♪ I kinda like the way she dips ♪
♪ But she's my best friend's girl ♪
♪ She's my best friend's girl ♪
♪ But she used to be mine ♪
♪ You've got your nuclear boots ♪
♪ And your drip-dry glove ♪
♪ Ooh, when you bite your lip ♪
♪ It's some reaction to love ♪
♪ Here she comes again ♪
♪ When she's dancing 'neath the starry sky ♪
♪ Yeah, I think you'll flip ♪
♪ Here she comes again ♪
- ♪ When she's dancing 'neath the starry sky ♪  - ♪ Here she comes again ♪
♪ I kinda like the way like the way she dips ♪
♪ 'Cause she's my best friend's girl ♪
♪ She's my best friend's girl ♪
♪ And she used to be mine ♪
♪ She's so fine ♪
♪ Always dancing down the street ♪
♪ With your suede blue eyes ♪
♪ And every new boy that you meet ♪
♪ Doesn't know the real surprise ♪
♪ Here she comes again ♪
- ♪ When she's dancing 'neath the starry sky ♪  - ♪ Here she comes again ♪
♪ Ooh, she'll make you flip ♪
♪ Here she comes again ♪
- ♪ When she's dancing 'neath the starry sky ♪  - ♪ Here she comes again ♪
♪ I kinda like the way I like the way she dips ♪
♪ 'Cause she's my best friend's girl ♪
♪ She's my best friend's girl ♪
♪ She used to be mine ♪
♪ She's so fine ♪
♪ My best friend's girlfriend ♪
- ♪ My best friend's girlfriend ♪  - ♪ She used to be mine ♪
- ♪ My best friend's girlfriend ♪  - ♪ Yeah, yeah ♪
- ♪ My best friend's girlfriend ♪  - ♪ Yeah, yeah, yeah ♪
- ♪ My best friend's girlfriend ♪  - ♪ She used to be mine ♪
♪ My best friend's girlfriend ♪